Register of the Leo Eloesser Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Oversize Materials., 1919-1980s. (Box 44)
  - Photographs (Box 49)
    - One print depicting Leo Eloesser, 1951 (Folder 49: 4)
    - Two photocopies of a photograph depicting Leo Eloesser next to an automobile, undated (Folder 49: 5)
    - One photocopy of a collage comprised of eight photographs depicting Joyce Campbell, including two with Leo Eloesser, undated (Folder 49: 6)
    - One framed print depicting Dr. Barkan, 1930 (Folder 49: 7)
    - One print depicting Dr. Prat, Montevideo, Uruguay, 1946 April 24 (Folder 49: 8)
    - One print depicting Blanche Campbell and classmates, undated (Folder 49: 9)
    - One print depicting Claire Cleghorn, undated (Folder 49: 10)
    - One framed print depicting Leo Eloesser (grandfather), undated (Folder 49: 11)
    - One print depicting an unidentified person, undated (Folder 49: 12)
    - Six framed prints depicting unidentified persons and scenes, undated (Folder 49: 13-18)
    - One glass negative of a print depicting an unidentified person, undated (Folder 49: 19)
  - Memorabilia (Box 50)
    - Diplomas and awards
      - Two diplomas awarded to Leo Eloesser by Heidelberg University in completion of his medical studies, 1907 (Folder 50: 1-2)
      - One medallion, Sociedad Venezolana de tisiologia y neumonologia, 1937(?) (Folder 50: 3)
      - One diploma conferring honorary membership, Sociedad de cirujanos de Chile, Santiago de Chile, 1949 April 18 (Folder 50: 4)
      - One medallion, Sociedad Mexicana de neumologia y cirugia de torax, 1967 (Folder 50: 5)
      - One diploma conferring honorary membership, Asociación Centro Americana de tisiologia, undated (Folder 50: 6)
      - One medallion, Academia nacional de medicina, Mexico, undated (Folder 50: 7)
    - Miscellany
      - Six small posters relating to the American Expeditionary Forces, 1919 (Folder 50: 7-12)
      - One metal brooch with inscription, "por vuestra libertad y la nuestra,", ca. 1939 (Folder 50: 13)
      - One wooden carving depicting Leo Eloesser examining a horse, 1971 (Folder 50: 14)
      - One lapel pin, California Medical Association, undated (Folder 50: 15)
      - One statuette depicting a dachshund, undated (Folder 50: 16)
      - One pair of Chinese chopsticks (Folder 50: 17)
      - Three signature chops, China, undated (Folder 50: 18-20)
      - One thermometer, undated (Folder 50: 21)
      - One cigarette holder, undated (Folder 50: 22)
      - Two prescription pads, undated (Folder 50: 23-24)
  - Miscellany (Map-case Map Case)
    - One woodblock print depicting a caricature of Chiang Kai-shek and his allies, ca. 1944-1949 (Map-case Map Case)
    - One woodblock print depicting a dragon dance, ca. 1944-1949 (Map-case Map Case)
    - One woodblock print depicting Taoist and Buddhist deities, ca. 1944-1949 (Map-case Map Case)
    - One scroll painting by Xu Shiqi depicting a waterfall, 1946 (Map-case Map Case)
      Includes dedication in Chinese to Leo Eloesser
    - One reproduction of a painting by Chi Pai-shi depicting shrimp, undated (Map-case Map Case)
    - Three charcoal rubbings, China, undated (Map-case Map Case)
    - One large framed painting by Máximo Pacheco, undated (Art Art)
    - Three framed paintings by Pedro Figari, undated (Racks Racks)
    - One amateur painting, China, undated (Container Container)
      (Restricted due to extremely fragile condition.)